Amanpreet Kaur | Software Developer

647-870-1003 | amanpreet@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/amanpreet-kaur-software-engineering | github.com/amanpreet8507

PROFILE

Software developer with 2 years of experience building websites. Also, a BrainStation graduate that's passionate about web development & new technologies taking place. I challenge myself daily with LeetCode problem solving to enhance my confidence for technical implementation.

SKILLS

Python, C++, C#, Git, Github, Gitlab, Terminal, DOM, Object Oriented Programming, MySQL, MongoDB

Figma, User Research, UX Strategy, Personas, Prototyping, User Testing, UI Design

HTML, CSS, Web Servers, Sass, JavaScript, HTML5, Rest APIs, ReactJS, Node.js, Angular, ExpressJS, JQuery

PROJECTS

Software Developer(Product Manager, UX Designer) | Expense Ease

MAR 2023, CAPSTONE PROJECT

Expense Ease is a fully responsive & cloud application which keeps track of user's expenses on daily, monthly & yearly basis. It is built using ReactJS, Sass, JavaScript ES6, Agile methodologies, BEM, Git, Knex & Express for building Web Api, CRUD operations, Postman for API testing, MySQL Workbench as relational databases.

Software Developer(Lead Coder) | InStock

FEB 2023, BRAINSTATION HACKATHON

InStock keeps track of item inventories in Warehouses & allows businesses to operate CRUD for Warehouse & Inventory details. It is built using Figma for Web Design, ReactJS, JavaScript ES6, BEM, Sass, Git, Terminal, Jira, Knex & Express for building Web Api, SQL as relational databases, Schemas, Postman for API testing.

EDUCATION

Computer Systems Technology | Diploma, Computer Systems Technology

MAY 2022 - PRESENT, VANCOUVER, BC

BrainStation | Diploma, Software Engineering

DEC 2023 - MAR 2024, VANCOUVER, BC

EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer | Leafstash

FEB 2024 - PRESENT, VANCOUVER, BC

- Building & Focusing on Mobile framework & using React Native & Angular (TypeScript) for smooth workflows.
- Using Git & GitLab as version control systems to implement code changes & ClickUp as CMS for communication & organizational practices & collaborate with the team members
- Responsible for **testing** practices, **QA**, **documentation** & code review for easy maintenance & production support.

Coding Teaching Assistant | Cloverdale Robotics

SEP 2023 - JAN 2024, SURREY, BC

- Delivered computer science lessons related to programming languages to school kids, covering topics such as Scratch,
 Python & Web development & brainstorming with students to write & solve everyday code challenges.
- Organized timing for class lessons & prioritizing planned lessons to be delivered efficiently.